Mahdi Gharooni

Flutter Developer

SUMMARY

Skilled Mobile Developer with over 4 years of experience in Mobile Programming, including 3 years in Flutter development, and 1 year in Android development. Familiar with Mobile Native Languages(Java, Swift) and eager to learn more. Have mainly focused on building cross-platform applications with various features and contributing to open-source projects. Seeking a better role and willing to relocate anywhere.

SKILLS

Flutter, Dart, Android, Java, Kotlin, SQL, OPP, Design Patterns, Git, CI/CD, Unit testing, TDD, Firebase services, State management, Map, Platform channel, SocketIO, Android Studio, Swagger, Postman, Agile, Time management, Teamwork, Creativity, Problem solving

Familiar with: Swift, Javascript

EXPERIENCES

Pardakht Novin 🗗

(2 yrs) Jul 2020 - Present

<u>Flutter Developer</u> Tehran, Iran

Pardakht Novin Company is currently active in the field of electronic payment as one of the companies licensed by the Iran Central Bank.

- Publishing a financial cross-platform application by Flutter for Android, IOS and web platforms.
- Responsibility for refactoring application architecture by Repository Pattern and BLoC in Flutter, making it faster, more testable and legible.
- Developing new features through Java, Swift and Javascript in platform channels and growing 5% revenue.
- Debugging and Uploading the IOS version, increasing 10k new users.
- Adding some new services and fixing some old bugs, lead to attracting more than 5k new users.

Livecart 🗹

(1 yrs) Aug 2021 - Present

Flutter Developer

London, UK (Remote - part time)

Livecart is an innovative hyper-local real-time eCommerce platform, providing the most convenient local shopping experience, with the power to find, search and explore local offers on your everyday shopping for pickup or rapid delivery.

- Implementing more than 70% of the wrapper by InappFlutter webview for Android and IOS platforms.
- Communicating between Flutter and Javascript with a 50% growth in app efficiency.
- Programming Firebase services like Notifications and Analytics.
- Improving 30% of the speed and performance of the application by refactoring Flutter codes.

Tarafdari 🔀

(1 yrs 6 mos) Jan 2019 - Jun 2020

Tehran, Iran

Mobile Developer

Tarafdari is the first and most popular sports social media network with millions of users in Iran, providing official news and live scores of national and international matches.

- Publishing a sports news application for Android and IOS platforms by Flutter with over 50k users.
- Developed several features by using file-manager, charts and tables, led to attract 20k new users.
- Implementing TV Sports matches streaming with Live Chat on the SocketIO.
- Supporting Firebase services: Analytics, Notifications and Crashlytics.

PROJECTS

Flutter Docker Image 🗷 Feb 2020

- Uploading a Docker Image to use Flutter commands.
- Helping people to setup CI/CD, with over 400 downloads.

Idehshop ☑ May 2021

- Programming a location-based application by Flutter to display the nearest stores for users with online shopping, lead to 50% time saving.
- Helping sellers to register their stores and 10 to 30% increase in the number of sales.

CONTRIBUTIONS

Flutter/Flutter

HONORS AND AWARDS

• First Place in the 12th Iran Web and Mobile Festival.

EDUCATION

Shahid Rajaee Teacher Training University

Bachelor of Software Engineering

(4 yrs) Feb 2015 - Feb 2019 Tehran, Iran

LANGUAGES

Persian: Native Language English: Mid Advanced